<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | CDRL</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/cdrl_logo_square.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abdul-rizaq Hamoud Writes Column in Toledo Blade</title>
      <link>/post/accomplishments_abdul_may2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accomplishments_abdul_may2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:70.0%;height:70.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../authors/abdul&#34;&gt;Abdul-Rizaq Ali Hamoud&lt;/a&gt;, a Ph.D. student in the Neurosciences and Neurological Disorders track from the Cognitive Disorders Research Laboratory (CDRL) had his research story &amp;ldquo;UT researchers investigate unusual cancer rates in schizophrenia patients” published in The Blade this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.toledoblade.com/a-e/living/2022/05/02/university-of-toledo-medical-column-may-2-abdul-rizaq-hamoud-cancer-in-schizophrenic-patients/stories/20220502001&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nicholas Henkel receives Graduate Research Award for 2022</title>
      <link>/post/accomplishments_nick_may2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accomplishments_nick_may2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:40.0%;height:40.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../authors/nick&#34;&gt;Nicholas Henkel&lt;/a&gt;, an M.D./Ph.D. student in the Cognitive Disorders Research Laboratory (CDRL), was one of this year&amp;rsquo;s recipients of The University of Toledo Graduate Research Award. This award from the UToledo Graduate Student Association (GSA) will provide financial support toward their research projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten graduate students, as selected by the Graduate Council, recently received the Graduate Research Award for 2022 in conjunction with The University of Toledo College of Graduate Studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This was another competitive year and we received a number of applications that made it very difficult to pick and choose,” said &lt;a href=&#34;../authors/ali&#34;&gt;Ali Imami&lt;/a&gt;, president of the Graduate Students Association. “I would like to thank the members of the Graduate Council Student Affairs Committee and the College of Graduate Studies, who have worked tirelessly to systematically catalog, analyze, rate and rank these applications and then decided on the final recipients.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.utoledo.edu/index.php/03_30_2022/graduate-research-award-recipients-for-2022-announced&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Article Published in Hepatology</title>
      <link>/post/accomplishments_justin_march2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accomplishments_justin_march2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:70.0%;height:70.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drs. Justin Creeden, Khaled Alganem, Ali Imami, and Robert Smith recently published an article in Hepatology (Impact Factor 17.4) with Dr. Terry Hinds and collaborators at the University of Kentucky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper combines bioinformatic studies with basic science laboratory validation studies to generate the first kinome atlas for hepatic fibrosis. In this piece, we utilize human cirrhosis samples and three murine models of fibrosis to measure concordance between human and rodent hepatic kinome signaling. We also identify protein tyrosine kinases or serine/threonine kinases with altered levels of kinase activity in the fibrotic pathways of both species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35313030/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Khaled Alganem and William Ryan receive Class of 2022 Graduate Student Awards</title>
      <link>/post/accomplishments_khaled_billy_march2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accomplishments_khaled_billy_march2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:40.0%;height:40.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../authors/khaled&#34;&gt;Khaled Alganem&lt;/a&gt;, a Ph.D. student in the Cognitive Disorders Research Laboratory (CDRL), was awarded the &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doctor of Philosophy in Biomedical Sciences Outstanding Student&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; award of this year&amp;rsquo;s College of Medicine and Life Sciences (COMLS) Graduation Awards. &lt;a href=&#34;../authors/billy&#34;&gt;William (Billy) Ryan&lt;/a&gt;, a Master&amp;rsquo;s student in the Cognitive Disorders Research Laboratory (CDRL), also received the &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Master of Science in Biomedical Sciences Basic Science Research Outstanding Student&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; award.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.utoledo.edu/med/depts/cancer-biology/faculty/williams.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Kandace Williams&lt;/a&gt;, the Senior Associate Dean for College of Medicine &amp;amp; Life Sciences Graduate, congratulated all the awardees: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;You all have worked long and hard for these highest Awards of the College of Medicine and Life Sciences and you well deserve them! I am very proud of you all and very excited to let you know that you are the top graduate student winners in your respective programs of 2022!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Class of 2022 Graduation Awards Ceremony will be “live” Thursday May 19 from 3 – 5 PM in the Collier Building, Rm 1000A/B to honor the awards recipients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to &lt;a href=&#34;../authors/khaled&#34;&gt;Khaled&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;../authors/billy&#34;&gt;Billy&lt;/a&gt; for these outstanding achievements!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rawan Alnafisah Writes Column in Toledo Blade</title>
      <link>/post/accomplishments_rawan_february2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accomplishments_rawan_february2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:70.0%;height:70.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../authors/rawan&#34;&gt;Rawan Alnafisah&lt;/a&gt;, a Ph.D. student in the Molecular Medicine track from the Cognitive Disorders Research Laboratory (CDRL) had her research story &amp;ldquo;UT researchers look for answers to depression on a molecular level” published in the Blade this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.toledoblade.com/a-e/culture/2022/02/07/university-of-toledo-medical-research-on-depression/stories/20220207001&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Ali Imami is Awarded Scholarship to Attend Conference on Genome Informatics</title>
      <link>/post/accomplishments_ali_september2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accomplishments_ali_september2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:25.0%;height:25.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to &lt;a href=&#34;../authors/ali&#34;&gt;Ali Sajid Imami&lt;/a&gt;, a Ph.D. student working in the Department of Neurosciences Cognitive Disorders Research Lab under Dr. Robert McCullumsmith, who was recently awarded a prestigious James P. Taylor Foundation for Open Science Scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ali was one of only ten outstanding graduate students in genomics and data sciences to receive this honor. The scholarship covers the full conference registration for the 2021 Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory conference on Genome Informatics being held in November. Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory is a leading international center for research and education and facilitates advanced technical science courses, with organizers, instructors and participants from all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year’s conference will cover a wide range of Informatics topics including Microbial and Metagenomics, Sequencing Algorithms, Variant Discovery and Genome Assembly, Evolution, Complex Traits and Phylogenetics, Functional Genomics, Single Cell Genomics and Epigenetics and Genome Structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jxtxfoundation.org/news/2021-08-jxtx-awardees/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Learn More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Article Featured by Nature Communication Biology</title>
      <link>/post/accomplishments_khaled_august2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accomplishments_khaled_august2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:25.0%;height:25.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../authors/rob&#34;&gt;Dr. Robert McCullumsmith&lt;/a&gt;, Chair of the Department of Neurosciences, and Ph.D. candidate &lt;a href=&#34;../authors/khaled&#34;&gt;Khaled Alganem&lt;/a&gt; (pictured) recently published an article in Molecular Psychiatry (Impact Factor 12.4) with collaborators at the University of Alabama at Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper explores the disrupted mTOR signaling in schizophrenia and studied the expression and activity of downstream effector proteins of mTOR complexes. The paper also demonstrates key differences in kinase signaling networks between schizophrenia and comparison subjects for both males and females using kinome peptide arrays. The role of mTOR kinase activity is further investigated by inhibiting it with rapamycin in postmortem tissue and comparing the impact of mTOR inhibition in schizophrenia and comparison subjects. It was found that schizophrenia subjects are globally more sensitive to rapamycin treatment and AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) contributes to this differential kinase activity. Together, The findings provide new insights into the role of mTOR as a master regulator of kinase activity in schizophrenia and suggest potential targets for therapeutic intervention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article was recently featured in the research highlights of Nature Communications Biology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s42003-021-02270-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Learn More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Sinead O’Donovan Serves as a Reviewer for NIMH</title>
      <link>/post/accomplishments_sinead_june2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accomplishments_sinead_june2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:25.0%;height:25.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to &lt;a href=&#34;../authors/sinead&#34;&gt;Dr. Sinead O’Donovan&lt;/a&gt;, assistant professor in the Department of Neurosciences, who was selected to serve as an early career reviewer on the Pathophysiological Basis of Mental Disorders (PBMD) and Addictions Study Section at the National Institute of Mental Health. This opportunity will provide her with an insider’s view of how grant applications are evaluated, allowing her to improve her grant writing skills and develop research-evaluation and critique-writing skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Early Career Review Program at the National Institutes of Health (NIH) aims to help early career scientists become more competitive as grant applicants through first-hand experience with peer review and to enrich and diversify the Center for Scientific Review’s pool of trained reviewers. Early career reviewers work side-by-side with some of the most accomplished researchers in their field to help NIH identify the most promising grant applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Awards for Grantsmanship Announced at The University of Toledo</title>
      <link>/post/accomplishments_rob_june2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accomplishments_rob_june2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:25.0%;height:25.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University of Toledo recognized faculty members who secured external support for their research programs over the 2018-20 period with the 2021 Awards for Grantsmanship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In many disciplines, particularly those based on laboratory research, financial demands for personnel support such as students, equipment, supplies and travel far exceed what the University can provide, so external grant support is necessary to support a faculty member’s research,” said Dr. Frank Calzonetti, vice president for research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../authors/rob&#34;&gt;Dr. Robert McCullumsmith&lt;/a&gt; was among the faculty members who were recognized for 2021 Awards for Grantsmanship during a May ceremony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.utoledo.edu/index.php/06_03_2021/2021-awards-for-grantsmanship-announced&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Learn More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Ali Imami Receives University Fellowship</title>
      <link>/post/accomplishments_ali_june2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accomplishments_ali_june2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:25.0%;height:25.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to recent master&amp;rsquo;s graduate &lt;a href=&#34;../authors/ali&#34;&gt;Ali Sajid Imami&lt;/a&gt;. The College of Graduate Studies has awarded Ali the prestigious University Fellowship for the 2021-2022 academic school year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University Fellowship is the highest award granted to an incoming graduate student by the College of Graduate Studies and is extended only to doctoral students of exceptional ability and promise. In April, Ali defended his thesis for his Master of Science in Biomedical Science Bioinformatics, Proteomics &amp;amp; Genomics. We look forward to hearing great things from Ali in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDRL Bioinformatics Hackathon 2021</title>
      <link>/post/bioinformatics_hackathon_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/bioinformatics_hackathon_2021/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.png&#34; style=&#34;width:65.0%;height:65.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CDRL Annual Bioinformatics Hackathon is an event that brings the
best and brightest together to focus on solving a standing problem in
Bioinformatics. This competition aims to ignite people’s imaginations
and to spur them into action utilizing both older and modern techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The 2021 Bioinformatics Hackathon will take place&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;April 14-16&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
The theme of this hackathon is “&lt;strong&gt;Mine this Dataset&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;timeline&#34;&gt;Timeline:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last Date to Register: Sunday, April 4th, 2021. &lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/YNQw9bDaLMjTJ8yb7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Register
Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dataset Reveal: 8 AM, April 14th, 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inaugural Session: 10 AM, April 14th, 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;First Impressions Session: 3 PM, April 14th, 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Progress Check In: 12 PM, April 15th, 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Final Presentations: 2 PM, April 16th, 2021&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;guidelines&#34;&gt;Guidelines:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Teams should consist of 2-4 players&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;No swapping of teammates will be allowed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each team will be provided with a dedicated set of tools in a remote
high performance cluster environment. No other computing resources
will be allowed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any tools or scripts developed in the process should be released
under an open-source compatible license&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;judges&#34;&gt;Judges:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Robert E. McCullumsmith&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Jarek Meller&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Rammohan Shukla&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Sinead O’Donovan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;prizes&#34;&gt;Prizes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;First Prize: $500 and a plaque&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second Prize: $300 and a plaque&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Third Prize: $100 and a certificate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Honorable Mentions: A certificate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Every team that participates will get a certificate of participation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Ali Imami Writes Column in Toledo Blade</title>
      <link>/post/accomplishments_ali_march2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accomplishments_ali_march2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:25.0%;height:25.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../authors/ali&#34;&gt;Dr. Ali Imami&lt;/a&gt;, a Ph.D. student in the Bioinformatics track from the Cognitive Disorders Research Laboratory (CDRL) had his research story &amp;ldquo;UT researchers investigate cell communication and disease” published in the Blade this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.toledoblade.com/a-e/culture/2021/03/01/ut-researchers-investigate-complex-nature-of-cell-communication/stories/20210301003&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justin Creeden Writes Column in Toledo Blade</title>
      <link>/post/accomplishments_justin_december2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accomplishments_justin_december2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:70.0%;height:70.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M.D./Ph.D. student &lt;a href=&#34;../authors/justin&#34;&gt;Justin Creeden&lt;/a&gt; wrote a column in the Toledo Blade about using technology to aid in researching cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I combine traditional laboratory research methods that use Petri dishes, test tubes, and microscopes with computational biology techniques that use mathematical modeling and simulations to answer important research questions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../authors/justin&#34;&gt;Justin Creeden&lt;/a&gt; is doing his doctoral research in the laboratory of Dr. Robert McCullumsmith, in the Department of Neurosciences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.toledoblade.com/news/medical/2020/12/07/university-of-toledo-research-turns-supercomputers-toward-cancer-research/stories/20201207001&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Read Article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
