<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CDRL</title>
    <link>/authors/cdrl/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/cdrl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CDRL</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>CDRL</title>
      <link>/authors/cdrl/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Sinead O’Donovan Serves as a Reviewer for NIMH</title>
      <link>/post/accomplishments_sinead_june2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accomplishments_sinead_june2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:25.0%;height:25.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to &lt;a href=&#34;../../authors/sinead&#34;&gt;Dr. Sinead O’Donovan&lt;/a&gt;, assistant professor in the Department of Neurosciences, who was selected to serve as an early career reviewer on the Pathophysiological Basis of Mental Disorders (PBMD) and Addictions Study Section at the National Institute of Mental Health. This opportunity will provide her with an insider’s view of how grant applications are evaluated, allowing her to improve her grant writing skills and develop research-evaluation and critique-writing skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Early Career Review Program at the National Institutes of Health (NIH) aims to help early career scientists become more competitive as grant applicants through first-hand experience with peer review and to enrich and diversify the Center for Scientific Review’s pool of trained reviewers. Early career reviewers work side-by-side with some of the most accomplished researchers in their field to help NIH identify the most promising grant applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Ali Imami Receives University Fellowship</title>
      <link>/post/accomplishments_ali_june2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accomplishments_ali_june2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;featured.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:25.0%;height:25.0%&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to recent master&amp;rsquo;s graduate &lt;a href=&#34;../../authors/ali&#34;&gt;Ali Sajid Imami&lt;/a&gt;. The College of Graduate Studies has awarded Ali the prestigious University Fellowship for the 2021-2022 academic school year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University Fellowship is the highest award granted to an incoming graduate student by the College of Graduate Studies and is extended only to doctoral students of exceptional ability and promise. In April, Ali defended his thesis for his Master of Science in Biomedical Science Bioinformatics, Proteomics &amp;amp; Genomics. We look forward to hearing great things from Ali in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
