<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cancer | CDRL</title>
    <link>//localhost:4321/tags/cancer/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:4321/tags/cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Cancer</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:4321/img/cdrl_logo_square.png</url>
      <title>Cancer</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/tags/cancer/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>cBioPortal</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/project/public_resources/cbioportal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/project/public_resources/cbioportal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cBioPortal for Cancer Genomics is an open-access, open-source resource for interactive exploration of multidimensional cancer genomics data sets. The goal of cBioPortal is to significantly lower the barriers between complex genomic data and cancer researchers by providing rapid, intuitive, and high-quality access to molecular profiles and clinical attributes from large-scale cancer genomics projects, and therefore to empower researchers to translate these rich data sets into biologic insights and clinical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genomic Data Commons Data Portal</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/project/public_resources/gdc_portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/project/public_resources/gdc_portal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The National Cancer Institute Genomic Data Commons (GDC) is an information system for storing, analyzing, and sharing genomic and clinical data from patients with cancer. The recent high-throughput sequencing of cancer genomes and transcriptomes has produced a big data problem that precludes many cancer biologists and oncologists from gleaning knowledge from these data regarding the nature of malignant processes and the relationship between tumor genomic profiles and treatment response. The GDC aims to democratize access to cancer genomic data and to foster the sharing of these data to promote precision medicine approaches to the diagnosis and treatment of cancer. The GDC Data Portal is a robust data-driven platform that allows cancer researchers and bioinformaticians to search and download cancer data for analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proteomic Data Commons (PDC)</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/project/public_resources/pdc_portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/project/public_resources/pdc_portal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The objectives of the National Cancer Institute’s Proteomic Data Commons (PDC) are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to make cancer-related proteomic datasets easily accessible to the public&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;facilitate multiomic integration in support of precision medicine through interoperability with other resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PDC was developed to advance our understanding of how proteins help to shape the risk, diagnosis, development, progression, and treatment of cancer. In-depth analysis of proteomic data allows us to study both how and why cancer develops and to devise ways of personalizing treatment for patients using precision medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PDC is one of several repositories within the NCI Cancer Research Data Commons (CRDC), a secure cloud-based infrastructure featuring diverse data sets and innovative analytic tools – all designed to advance data-driven scientific discovery. The CRDC enables researchers to link proteomic data with other data sets (e.g., genomic and imaging data) and to submit, collect, analyze, store, and share data throughout the cancer data ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
